### KWASI OFORI-TWENEBOAH

## **Frontend Developer**

**Location:** Accra, Ghana **Telephone:** +233 24 363 7581

Email: tweneboah21@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/kotweneboah

#### **SUMMARY**

Budding frontend developer with a strong background of 10+ years' experience building, managing and maintaining visually appealing, functional and user friendly websites, using Joomla and WordPress. Built, hosted and managed 30+ websites in the space of 3 years. Proficient in HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Also have good working knowledge in AWS cloud technologies, Git and GitHub.

#### **SKILLS**

Joomla	WordPress	Elementor	WooCommerce	Git	GitHub
Python	JavaScript	React	CSS	HTML	AWS

#### **WORK HISTORY**

## Freelance Web Developer

09/2019 - Present

- Develop aesthetic websites and ecommerce applications using WordPress, Elementor and third party themes and plugins, HTML and CSS.
- Facilitate the establishment of the digital presence clients with a corresponding increase in business and revenue by 10%.

**Technical Sourcer** 

ITPros, LLC - Philadelphia, PA, USA

01/2022 - 09/2022

- Sourced for top Tech candidates for ready to fill roles in modern Tech companies, meeting high and stringent requirements such as candidates living in certain time zones and tech stack.
- Engaged in weekly departmental hangouts and team meetings, collaborating with global team members.

Founder/Developer

Taskjo Systems

08/2017 - 06/2019

 Engineered a cutting-edge micro-task marketplace web application akin to Upwork or Freelancer, facilitating seamless connections between individuals and businesses seeking specific talents and adept professionals keen on trading expertise for financial gain. • Administered a 2 member staff to launch the Taskjo project, which had close to 5 people sign up within the first week.

#### Founder/Web Developer

Webkitz LLC - Accra, Ghana

05/2010 - 04/2013

- Crafted websites for 30+ clients, spanning elegant landing pages to comprehensive e-commerce sites, yielding a notable 5-10% business growth across the board.
- Optimized website updates and maintenance procedures for over 10 clients, culminating in a 25% decrease in project turnaround time and an impressive 40% elevation in client contentment.
- Spearheaded company expansion from a foundation of two (2) personnel to a robust team of 10 by the end of 2012.

## **Systems Engineer (Contract)**

Barron Distilleries - Accra, Ghana

09/2008 - 04/2010

- Strategized, executed, and oversaw the establishment of the company's Client-Server Architecture, and Active Directory setup, resulting in a 20% improvement in network efficiency and streamlined user management.
- Orchestrated end-to-end processes for procuring, installing, and launching the company's ERP, Stock, and Account Management systems, resulting in a 30% increase in workflow efficiency.
- Conducted comprehensive on-site training sessions for both staff and management, enhancing system adoption by 95% and reducing operational errors by 50%.

# **Maintenance Engineer/Branch Manager** FATECO LTD - Accra, Ghana

11/2005 - 12/2007

- Managed primary maintenance and repair works in the factory but called in external service providers whenever necessary.
- Facilitated the growth of the branch by growing the client base by 30%, improved product quality by 50% thereby reducing loses.

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

04/2023 - 12/2023	Frontend Development (JavaScript/React)
	Azubi Africa – Accra
01/2023 - 04/2023	AWS re/Start Program Learner (AWS CCP Certification)
	Azubi Africa – Accra
01/2021 - 12/2023	Bachelor of Commerce
	Amity University Online - India
11/2007 - 08/2008	Networking Essentials Plus (N+) / Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer
	IPMC Training Center – Accra